Finding Aid for Daughters of the American Revolution. Menominee Chapter (Menominee, Mich.) records, 1905-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Daughters of the American Revolution. Menominee Chapter (Menominee, Mich.) records 1905-1974
Daughters of the American Revolution. Menominee Chapter (Menominee, Mich.).
2 linear feet
85125 Be.1 2
Secretary's books, financial records, membership material, and press and publicity books.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan (donor no. 1171 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Menominee Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution was organized February 28,1905. It was chartered January 11,1908 and disbanded October 10, 1974.
The record groups consists of minutes of meetings, financial and membership records, press and publicity materials, and various topical files detailing the chapter's activities.
Subjects:
Menominee (Mich.).; Patriotic societies--Michigan--Menominee.; Women--Michigan--Menominee--Societies and clubs.
- Organizational records
  - Secretary books
    - 1924-1930 (Box 1)
    - 1930-1949 (Box 1)
    - 1949-1963 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1974 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer books
    - 1918-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1945-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1969 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's reports in notebook, 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Historian Books
    - 1905-1924 (Box 1)
    - 1924-1956 (Box 1)
  - Regent's meeting books
    - 1963-1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Press books and publicity books
    (include scattered photographs)
    - 1932-1933, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 1)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1940 (Box 1)
    - 1954-1961 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1968 (Box 2)
      (unbound volume)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 2)
  - Convention reports -- papers written by members, 1906, 1910, 1911, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Papers by Bertha Greene, 1917-1918 (Box 2)
  - History of Chapter, 1935-1936 and 1937-1938 (Box 2)
  - Washington, D.C. and Mount Vernon postcards and photographs (Box 2)
  - DAR Ritual 1951 (Box 2)
  - The DAR -- magazine published by Boy's Club of Menominee, 1924-1927 (Box 2)
  - Year books and programs
    - 1944 (Box 2)
    - 1947-1951 (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Notebook containing miscellaneous correspondence and information (Box 2)
  - Ledger containing membership papers (Box 2)
    (returned to donor, March 2006)
  - Registrar's File Cards and miscellaneous forms (Box 2)
  - Membership card file box (Box 2)
  - Membership List & Committees, 1936-1942 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)